wow cool barrel our bandera ukraine
ух ты круто бочку наш бандера украина
mate we are for ukraine 0 in
мат мы за украину 0 в
ukraine from ukraine we wish where from
украине из украины желаем на откуда
home
дома
we are from russia along the highway from Donetsk you
мы из россии по шоссе из донецка вы по
could sing in ukrainian from
украински из могли спеть от nc откуда из
nc  you are Tatars
казань карваль на вы татары
before Tatars challenge Ukraine so
до татары вызов украина так
glory to Ukraine heroes glory added
слава украине героям слава добавлен
nation
нацию
look at you so that schoolchildren or
посмотри у вас чтобы школьники или
students are already schoolchildren when they teach at
студенты уже школьники сдавали когда у
your school
вас в школе
in Tatar or in Russian
обучают на татарском или на русском
some schools in which
каких-то школы в которых
mathematics here these schools
математика вот этих школ
feel there is mathematics royal is not
чувствует есть математика царском не
taught  on a string of tarko-sale schools
преподается на нитку тарко-сале школах
avant-garde schools there is in tatarstan yes a lot of
авангард школ есть татарстане да много
authorship 90 92 wanted to get independence
авторством 90 92 независимость хотел
but the tatar language is very dying almost
но татарский язык очень умирает почти
[music]
[музыка]
45 percent 5 10 already tatar language
45 процент 5 10 уже татарский язык а
but you know tatar but
вот вы знаете татарский а
why do you know about a friend i don’t know because
почему вы знаете о друге не знаю потому
to learn  boards at school, why
что научиться доски школе ну а почему
did you teach and 2 not scientists because of
это вы учили и 2 не ученного из-за
something burning
чего-то жгучий
putin made this choice schoolchildren can
путин сделал этот выбор школьники могут
collect  to teach either Russian or
собирать учить либо русские либо
Tatar types, many are simple and nothing at all,
татарские типы многие просто и вообще не
it
что дальше
turns out that you don’t have to take it on
получается что его не надо сдавать на
exams for euro years, but only to your husband about
экзаменах евро лет но уже только мужу о
food in Russian at the game and money,
еде на русском на игре и денег
that is, mathematics there you just do
то есть математику там вы просто по
mathematics for the Tatarstan league and this is
математике на татарстана лига и такое
also on  Russian gets money
тоже на русском получается деньгам
because of this, everything is taught by Russians on the
из-за этого все и учат русские по
gate, do it, and that’s how it kills the
воротам поступай да вот то так и убивает
languages of the year, but do you
языки года а
hink there is an opportunity to improve thi
вот как вы считаете есть возможность
situation that more people spoke Tatar
улучшить эту ситуацию что больше людей
there, but now they we
там на татарском говорила общалась но
e a very good Tatar camp now serves
вот были очень хорошим татарском лагерь
ithout  all these projectors
теперь подает без всяких эти проекторы
there was a business project of one team
там был бизнес проект одной команды
that you can’t buy but hang the
которые не купишь но по развесят
Estorian language there all sorts of things
эсторского языка там всякие
in which business project you earn money on
в чем бизнес проект на этом деньги
this it’s more like a social project a
заработаешь это скорее социальный проект
lot of ladies choose a business project and a
много дам выбираешь бизнес-проект и
project in the main project and choose
проект в основном проект и выбираешь
any environmental or social or
любом экологический либо социальные либо
business  bomb is social boss
бизнес бомба это социально босса
chooses no art won the
выбирает без искусства выиграл
social project investing
социальный проект инвестирование
well here by  accepting the trick of this
хорошо тут понимающим фишка этого
social project how to motivate a
социального проекта как смотивировать
person that youth writes Tatar
человека вот та молодёжь пишет татарский
I don’t know if I’m here if there are schools
я не знаю если я здесь есть если школы
if universities are all but the author
если университеты все но автор
leaves in Russian so the news in
оставляет на русском так новости на
Russian shops in Russian all this
русском магазины на русском все это
turns out to be Tatar then
получается татарские то как латыни
you know some kind of Latin so you need to  it’s not just
какая-то знаешь поэтому надо не просто
that it needs to be taught, the template must remain a
чтобы его учили надо шаблон оставалось
living language, that is, it should be on
живым языком то есть он должен быть и на
television and on store signs
телевидении и в на вывесках магазинов
completely like
полностью вот так
this,
вот у
according to the Tatar history there, you
вас по татарской там истории вы
get in the old Russian empire
получается в старый российской империи
from what year,
из какого года
I don’t know Tess,
это я не знаю тесс
I’m a techie, well  like a quiet history of his
я технарь ну как тихая историю своего
people, approximately he really is a
народа приблизительно он действительно а
techie why technok programmers
технарь почему технок программисты
engineers
инженеры
engineer and come on and at school an engineer can
инженер а ну-ка и в школе инженер может
be a nervous police spokes well what do
быть же нервной милиции спицами ну а что
you learn but how to do projects all sorts of
что учите но как проекты делать всякие
engineers we have a lot
инженеры очень много у
of equipment and special it
нас оборудования и специальных это
turns out like  like a vocational school,
получается как как профтехучилище
it’s like after the 9th grade for the
это как бы после 9 класса на
leader,
лидера
I know what’s there at the Kazan
я знаю что там при казанском
University  university there is a lyceum mathematical
университете есть лицей математический
radio physics and mathematics
радио физмат
perhaps it becomes good let's
возможно становится им хорошо давайте
run I continue to pray and further and
побежал я дальше молиться и дальше и